Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today, Marco, we're talking about something that I know you're a big fan of.
今天，Marco，我们要聊一个我知道你特别喜欢的话题。
I am.
是的。
We're talking about computer games, video games.
我们要聊电脑游戏、电子游戏。
So yeah, we're going to be looking at some vocabulary and phrases related to computer
所以，我们会看一些与电脑游戏和电子游戏相关的词汇和短语。
games and video games.
以及电子游戏。
And this is actually a request from one of our users.
这其实是来自我们一位用户的请求。
Awesome.
太棒了。
So before we get started, we do have the name of the game that we're going to look at.
在开始之前，我们确实有今天要看的游戏名称。
So let's listen to that in today's vocabulary preview.
那我们先听听今天的词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So the game that we're going to preview today is called Counter Strike.
我们今天要预览的游戏叫《反恐精英》。
Okay.
好的。
So first you have a strike or an attack.
首先，你有一个“strike”或攻击。
Right.
对。
Then you have a counter strike.
然后你有一个“counter strike”。
So that's an opposite attack or something like that.
所以那是一种反击或类似的东西。
Right.
对。
So it's a reaction to the first thing that happens.
所以它是对第一个事件的反应。
So you hit me and my counter strike is I hit you back.
你打我，我的反击就是打回去。
And this game is actually very, very popular all over the world because many players are
这个游戏实际上在全世界都非常非常流行，因为很多玩家可以同时竞技。
able to compete at the same time.
可以同时竞技。
So it's a shooting game.
所以它是一个射击游戏。
You shoot each other.
你们互相射击。
You are the terrorists and then the other team is like the police or the army or whatever.
你们是恐怖分子，另一队是警察或军队之类的。
Wow.
哇。
Sounds really exciting.
听起来真刺激。
Well, we're going to learn more about the specific vocab that goes with computer games
我们马上会学到更多关于电脑游戏和电子游戏的特定词汇。
and video games in a minute.
和电子游戏的特定词汇。
But first, let's take a listen to our dialogue.
但首先，我们来听一下对话。
Mark, where have you been?
Mark，你去哪儿了？
I've been calling you all morning.
我整个早上都在给你打电话。
I've been playing computer games.
我一直在玩电脑游戏。
What?
什么？
So you blew me off yesterday and today over a stupid video game.
所以你昨天放我鸽子，今天又因为一个破游戏不理我。
What game is so important that you have no time for me anymore?
什么游戏这么重要，让你都没时间理我了？
What are you playing?
你在玩什么？
It's called Counter Strike.
叫《反恐精英》。
It's a first person shooter game.
它是一个第一人称射击游戏。
It's awesome.
太棒了。
It's a multiplayer game where you can go online and compete against players from all over
它是一个多人游戏，你可以上网和来自世界各地的玩家竞技。
the world.
来自世界各地的玩家。
You've been wasting your time on this?
你就把时间浪费在这上面？
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信。
It doesn't even look fun or challenging.
它看起来既不好玩也没挑战性。
My laptop is on my bed.
我的笔记本电脑在床上。
If you think it's so easy, then get online and try to beat me.
如果你觉得这么简单，那就上线试试打败我。
Fine.
行。
Go, go, go.
冲，冲，冲。
Take the point.
占领据点。
Taking fire.
遭到射击。
Need assistance.
需要支援。
Damn it.
该死。
How are you killing me with a single shot?
你怎么一枪就把我打死了？
It's not fair.
这不公平。
I don't want to play anymore.
我不想玩了。
Let's go get something to eat.
我们出去吃点东西吧。
Can you bring me something?
你能给我带点东西吗？
I'm totally hooked on this game.
我完全迷上这个游戏了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So there was some really interesting vocab here.
这里有一些非常有趣的词汇。
And so let's look at it now in Language Takeaway.
我们现在在“语言要点”里看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, so what kind of a game was this, Marco?
好的，Marco，这是什么类型的游戏？
All right.
好的。
So the game was a FPS or also in the dialogue we heard a first person shooter game.
这个游戏是FPS，或者我们在对话里听到的“first person shooter game”（第一人称射击游戏）。
So our users might have heard this phrase first person before because it's a grammar
我们的用户可能以前听过“first person”这个短语，因为它在语法上有很多用法。
term in many ways.
在很多方面。
Right.
对。
We talk about I.
我们谈论“我”。
I do this.
我做这个。
I can sing.
我会唱歌。
That's the first person.
那是第一人称。
But when we're talking about games, first person shooter means that what you do, you're
但当我们谈论游戏时，第一人称射击意味着你做的事情，就像你是游戏中的角色一样。
doing as if you were the character in the game.
就像你是游戏中的角色一样。
Right.
对。
So even the way that you're looking at the game, it seems like you're looking through
甚至你看游戏的方式，也像是通过角色的眼睛在看。
the eyes of the character.
通过角色的眼睛。
Okay, so you don't see the body.
好的，所以你看不到身体。
You are the body of the person.
你就是那个人的身体。
You are the body.
你就是身体。
Exactly.
没错。
So first person shooter.
所以是第一人称射击。
So shooter obviously means that this is a shooting game.
“Shooter”显然意味着这是一个射击游戏。
What you do is you pull the trigger and shoot people.
你做的就是扣动扳机射击别人。
Exactly.
没错。
And as we mentioned, a lot of players are able to compete against each other.
正如我们提到的，很多玩家可以互相竞技。
So it's called a multiplayer game.
所以它叫多人游戏。
Okay, so multi is a prefix.
好的，“multi”是一个前缀。
It goes at the beginning of a word.
它放在单词的开头。
In English that means many.
在英语里它表示“很多”。
Many.
很多。
So it can be either multi-colored or multi-ethnic.
所以可以是“multi-colored”（多色的）或“multi-ethnic”（多民族的）。
And the meaning of this is that there are many different colors or many different ethnicities
多色的或多民族的。
or in this case, multiplayer, many different players at the same time.
而在这里，多人游戏意味着很多玩家同时在线。
Exactly.
没错。
So in this game, many players can play whether it's in a local area network or online over
所以在这个游戏里，很多玩家可以玩，无论是在局域网还是通过互联网在线。
the internet.
通过互联网在线。
Cool.
酷。
So you actually have to have the internet, right, when you're doing this because you're
所以当你玩的时候，实际上需要联网，对吧，因为你用的是很多不同的电脑。
using many different computers.
很多不同的电脑。
So they have to be connected to each other.
所以它们必须互相连接。
Right.
对。
So and that's our next word.
这就是我们的下一个词。
It's called go online in order to play.
它叫“go online”（上线）来玩。
Okay, so online you've heard before.
好的，“online”你以前听过。
Online means on the internet.
“Online”意思是在互联网上。
But in this case, the action of using the internet is called going online.
但在这里，使用互联网这个动作叫“going online”。
So I want to go online to read my email.
所以我想上线看我的邮件。
Right.
对。
Or I can't go online.
或者我不能上线。
I don't have a connection.
我没有连接。
My mom won't let me go online.
我妈妈不让我上线。
I'm in trouble.
我惹麻烦了。
All right.
好的。
So this is the way that you use it.
这就是它的用法。
You go online.
你上线。
In order to use the internet, you go online.
为了使用互联网，你需要上网。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
Well, the last word we've got here in language takeaway is a very important one when we talk
好了，我们在“语言点”部分要讲的最后一个词非常重要，尤其是当我们谈论
about video games because many people are in this situation.
电子游戏的时候，因为很多人都有这种情况。
They're hooked on video games.
他们沉迷于电子游戏。
Right.
没错。
So if you are hooked on a video game or you are hooked on anything, it means you're kind
所以，如果你沉迷于某个电子游戏或任何东西，意思就是你有点
of addicted or you're very, very interested in something.
上瘾了，或者你对某件事非常非常感兴趣。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So I'm hooked on the TV show True Blood.
所以我沉迷于电视剧《真爱如血》。
I love to watch it and I love, every day I run home so I can watch it.
我很喜欢看，每天都会跑回家去看。
But is there a game that you're hooked on, Marco?
但是，Marco，有没有你沉迷的游戏呢？
Currently, I am hooked on a game called Guitar Hero Metallica.
目前，我沉迷于一个叫《吉他英雄：金属乐队》的游戏。
Ooh, fun.
哦，真有趣。
Yeah, it's really fun.
是啊，真的很好玩。
When I borrowed your PS3, I was hooked on Bad Company.
我借你PS3的时候，我沉迷于《战地：叛逆连队》。
They're great games.
那些游戏很棒。
It's very easy to get hooked on video games.
沉迷于电子游戏很容易。
Too easy.
太容易了。
All right.
好了。
So that's all the words we have for language takeaway.
这就是我们“语言点”部分要讲的所有词汇。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
我们再来听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Mark where have you been?
Mark，你去哪儿了？
I've been calling you all morning.
我给你打了一上午电话。
I've been playing computer games.
我一直在玩电脑游戏。
What?
什么？
So you blew me off yesterday and today over a stupid video game.
所以你昨天和今天都放我鸽子，就为了一个破游戏？
What game is so important that you have no time for me anymore?
什么游戏这么重要，让你都没时间陪我了？
What are you playing?
你在玩什么？
It's called Counter Strike.
叫《反恐精英》。
It's a first person shooter game.
是一款第一人称射击游戏。
It's awesome.
超棒的。
It's a multiplayer game where you can go online and compete against players from all over
这是一款多人在线游戏，你可以上网和来自世界各地的玩家
the world.
对战。
You've been wasting your time on this.
你就在这上面浪费时间？
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信。
It doesn't even look fun or challenging.
看起来既不好玩也没有挑战性。
My laptop is on my bed.
我的笔记本电脑在床上。
If you think it's so easy, then get online and try to beat me.
如果你觉得这么简单，那就上线来打败我啊。
Fine.
行。
Damn it.
该死。
How are you killing me with a single shot?
你怎么一枪就把我打死了？
It's not fair.
这不公平。
I don't want to play anymore.
我不想玩了。
Let's go get something to eat.
我们出去吃点东西吧。
Can you bring me something?
你能给我带点吃的吗？
I'm totally hooked on this game.
我完全沉迷于这个游戏了。
Alright, we're back and we have a couple of phrases that we want to look at, specifically
好了，我们回来了，我们还有几个短语要讲，具体来说
two phrases.
是两个短语。
So let's look at those now in Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看看“流利度提升”部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
So what's the deal?
怎么回事？
You blew me off yesterday and now you're not even going to say sorry?
你昨天放我鸽子，现在连句道歉都不说？
Alright, so blew me off.
好了，所以“blew me off”。
What do you mean when you say you blew me off yesterday?
你说“你昨天放我鸽子”是什么意思？
Okay, so let's take a look at the infinitive version of this phrase.
好的，我们来看看这个短语的原形。
So to blow someone off.
就是“to blow someone off”。
And they all go together.
它们是一起的。
It's a fixed phrase.
这是一个固定短语。
And this means to have an appointment with someone, but to not go.
意思是你和别人有约，但你没去。
So we had a date planned, but he blew me off.
所以我们本来约好了，但他放我鸽子了。
What a jerk.
真是个混蛋。
He didn't go.
他没去。
I went.
我去了。
Did he tell you that he wasn't going to go?
他有没有告诉你他不去了？
No.
没有。
So it's a surprise.
所以很意外。
It's like you expect someone to come meet you or do something with you, but they don't
就像你期待某人来见你或和你一起做某事，但他们什么也没说，
say anything and they don't go.
也没来。
So there's another word very similar to this one and it's to stand someone up, right?
还有一个词和这个很相似，就是“to stand someone up”，对吧？
Exactly.
完全正确。
So he stood me up.
所以他放我鸽子了。
He didn't come.
他没来。
He blew me off.
他放我鸽子了。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
Alright and what's our next phrase?
好了，下一个短语是什么？
To waste your time.
浪费时间。
Alright so the girlfriend in this case was like, you're wasting your time on these video
好的，所以在这个例子中，女朋友说，你把这些时间浪费在
games.
电子游戏上。
That means you're not getting anything out of this.
意思是你从这上面得不到任何好处。
You're not benefiting.
你没有受益。
It means that you could spend your time doing other things.
意思是你可以把时间花在做其他事情上。
So if you're wasting your time on video games, you're not being productive.
所以如果你把时间浪费在电子游戏上，你就没有效率。
Exactly so.
正是如此。
You're not learning anything.
你什么也没学到。
So your mother might say to you when you're a kid, don't waste your time on games.
所以当你还是个孩子的时候，你妈妈可能会对你说，不要把时间浪费在游戏上。
You should be studying.
你应该学习。
Okay, or he wastes a lot of time watching TV.
好的，或者他浪费很多时间看电视。
That's a common problem.
这是个常见问题。
Alright, so let's listen to this dialogue again real fast and we'll be back in a bit.
好了，我们快速再听一遍这段对话，一会儿回来。
Good luck.
祝你好运。
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
I've been calling you all morning.
我给你打了一上午电话。
I've been playing computer games.
我一直在玩电脑游戏。
What?
什么？
So you blew me off yesterday and today over a stupid video game.
所以你昨天和今天都放我鸽子，就为了一个破游戏？
What game is so important that you have no time for me anymore?
什么游戏这么重要，让你都没时间陪我了？
What are you playing?
你在玩什么？
It's called Counter Strike.
叫《反恐精英》。
It's a first person shooter game.
是一款第一人称射击游戏。
It's awesome.
超棒的。
It's a multi-player game where you can go online and compete against players from all over
这是一款多人在线游戏，你可以上网和来自世界各地的玩家
the world.
对战。
You've been wasting your time on this?
你就在这上面浪费时间？
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信。
It doesn't even look fun or challenging.
看起来既不好玩也没有挑战性。
My laptop is on my bed.
我的笔记本电脑在床上。
If you think it's so easy, then get online and try to beat me.
如果你觉得这么简单，那就上线来打败我啊。
Fine.
行。
Damn it! How are you killing me with a single shot? It's not fair!
该死！你怎么一枪就把我打死了？这不公平！
I don't want to play anymore! Let's go get something to eat.
我不想玩了！我们出去吃点东西吧。
Can you bring me something? I'm totally hooked on this game.
你能给我带点吃的吗？我完全沉迷于这个游戏了。
All right, so we talked about, you know, being hooked on TV shows and video games,
好了，我们刚才聊了沉迷于电视剧和电子游戏，
but this is actually a very big problem in some Asian countries specifically, right?
但这实际上在一些亚洲国家是个很严重的问题，对吧？
I've heard that. Actually, I heard that in Japan, Korea, and China specifically,
我听说过。实际上，我听说在日本、韩国，特别是中国，
there are psychological treatment centers for kids who are addicted to gaming.
有专门针对沉迷游戏孩子的心理治疗中心。
And so there's a big thing in the news in China recently where
最近中国新闻里有个大事，
there were parents who were sending their kids to this treatment center, rehab for games,
有家长把孩子送到这种治疗中心，也就是游戏戒断所，
and that actually they found out that the rehab center didn't know what they were doing,
结果发现那个戒断所根本不懂怎么治疗，
and they were giving the kids electroshock therapy to get them off games.
他们竟然给孩子用电击疗法来戒除游戏。
Really?
真的吗？
So the parents took their kids back.
所以父母把孩子带回去了。
That's scary.
那真吓人。
It is scary.
确实吓人。
I guess it's a very popular thing in Asian countries specifically, right? To play online,
我猜这在亚洲国家特别流行，对吧？就是上网玩游戏，
to go online. There's a lot of other factors that influence this, but
上网。还有很多其他因素影响这个，但是
I think it is like everything in excess is dangerous.
我觉得任何东西过度了都危险。
This is true. And actually, some people have been using this addiction
没错。而且实际上，有些人已经利用这种上瘾
to be a productive use of their time. So you have some people who play a game called World
来高效利用时间。所以有些人玩一个叫《魔兽
of Warcraft.
世界》的游戏。
Uh-huh, and they win money.
嗯哼，他们还能赢钱。
And they win money, and they sell things to other players all over the world.
他们赢钱，还向世界各地的其他玩家卖东西。
Right.
对。
And so you have these kids in America buying toys and like shields and-
所以美国有孩子买玩具、盾牌之类的——
And gold.
还有金币。
Gold from kids in, for example, Indonesia.
从比如印度尼西亚的孩子那里买金币。
Right.
对。
And the kid in Indonesia is making money.
而印度尼西亚的孩子在赚钱。
Right, right, right. And also, if they're really good, they go on to become professional gamers
对对对。而且如果他们真的很厉害，还能成为职业玩家，
and compete in world competitions and also test out new video games. So yeah,
参加世界比赛，还能测试新游戏。所以是的，
it has its advantages as well.
它也有好处。
Can you imagine what your business card would look like? Professional gamer.
你能想象你的名片上写什么吗？职业玩家。
Professional gamer. All right.
职业玩家。好吧。
That's all the time we have for today. We hope you enjoyed this lesson. And of course,
今天的时间就到这里。希望你喜欢这节课。当然，
if you have any questions, comments, or doubts, please come to our website,
如果你有任何问题、评论或疑问，请访问我们的网站，
EnglishPod.com, and we'll see you guys there.
EnglishPod.com，我们那里见。
Until next time, everyone.
下次再见，各位。
Bye.
拜拜。